Guide to the American Federation of Teachers Local 3412 Records, 1971-1980 AIS.1982.13
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Federation of Teachers, Local 3412 Records
1971-1980
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Federation of Teachers. Local 3412 (Robert Morris College, Coraopolis, Pa.)
AIS.1982.13
0.84 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Robert Morris College Faculty Federation, Local No. 3412 of the American Federation of Teachers was certified by the National Labor Relations Board on October 8, 1974 as the collective bargaining agent for full-time faculty of the college. This collection documents the disbandment of the Faculty Senate at Robert Morris College and the organization of Local 3412.
History
The Robert Morris College Faculty Federation, Local No. 3412 of the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) represents faculty at Robert Morris College in Moon Township, Pennsylvania. In March 1974 the Faculty Senate of Robert Morris College disbanded because it was deemed ineffective by its participants. In its place, an organizing committee proposed an AFT local that would represent the interests of full-time faculty on campus. After an election, the local was certified by the National Labor Relations Board on October 8, 1974 as the collective bargaining agent for its members.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection documents the disbandment of the Faculty Senate at Robert Morris College and the organization of the American Federation of Teachers Local 3412. Included are correspondence, AFT charter applications, National Labor Relations Board posters, and draft constitutions. Also present are information on contract negotiations and proposals.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
American Federation of Teachers, Local 3412 Records, 1971-1980, AIS.1982.13, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Gift of American Federation of Teachers, Local 3412 in 1982. An addition to this collection was included in 1983.
Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Coraopolis; Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Coraopolis; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Coraopolis; Labor; Education; Coraopolis (Pa.); American Federation of Teachers. Local 3412 (Robert Morris College, Coraopolis, Pa.) -- Records and correspondence; Robert Morris College (Coraopolis, Pa.)
- Faculty Senate, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Organization, March-April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Organization, April 16, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Organization, May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Organization, June-October 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Organization, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bargaining Unit Challenge, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Leaflets, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Salary Increases, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Unfair Labor Practices Charges, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Faculty Seniority, Rank and Salary, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Charter Application to American Federation of Teachers, AFL-CIO, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Robert Morris College Faculty Federation Constitution (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Collective Bargaining Agreement, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Communications on Negotiations, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Robert Morris College Faculty/Staff Directory, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Revised Contract Draft, July 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Contract Proposal, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
- Contract Proposal, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Proposed Contract, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Negotiation Minutes, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Communications on Negotiations, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Negotiations, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- federation report on Working Conditions, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Department of Education Evaluation of Robert Morris College, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Robert Morris College Audited Financial Statement, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Robert Morris College, Form 990, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Proposed Contract between Robert Morris College and Full-Time Faculty, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Communications, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Status Reports on Negotiations, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Negotiations, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
- Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)